<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Why use waziups on WAZIUP Platform</title>
    <link>/why-use-waziup/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Why use waziups on WAZIUP Platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/why-use-waziup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature list</title>
      <link>/why-use-waziup/feature-list</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-use-waziup/feature-list</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Waziup 0.1.0 includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP IoT Cloud platform offers cutting-edge IoT features and capabilities for your IoT products&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Device Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Manage million of IoT devices&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edge computing&lt;/strong&gt;: Light-weight IoT PaaS at gateway for computing and application&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IoT PaaS&lt;/strong&gt;: Offer git-push application development&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualization&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time and advanced historic analytic and visualization of information&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big data analytic&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time big data processing and analytic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users management&lt;/strong&gt;: Manage various user’s authentication and roles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy and security&lt;/strong&gt;: Offer policy based data access control&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Container framework&lt;/strong&gt;: Developed fully based on container framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users interface&lt;/strong&gt;:  Offer various users interface like SMS, voice call, mobile app, web app&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;admonition note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./documentation/installation/hello-world/&#34;&gt;Try Waziup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./why-use-waziup/use-cases/&#34;&gt;Use cases&lt;/a&gt;: Waziup solutions to practical problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./why-use-waziup/waziup-compared-to/&#34;&gt;What Waziup offers compared to other tools and services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./documentation/how-waziup-works/architecture-and-components/&#34;&gt;How Waziup works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frameworks and tools</title>
      <link>/why-use-waziup/waziup-compared-to/frameworks-and-tools</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-use-waziup/waziup-compared-to/frameworks-and-tools</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;waziup-compared-to&#34;&gt;Waziup compared to&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;admonition note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./documentation/installation/hello-world&#34;&gt;Try Waziup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./why-use-wziup/use-cases/&#34;&gt;Use cases&lt;/a&gt; -  some Waziup solutions to practical problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out &lt;a href=&#34;./documentation/how-waziup-works/architecture-and-components&#34;&gt;how Waziup works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started</title>
      <link>/why-use-waziup/get-started</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-use-waziup/get-started</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-waziup&#34;&gt;Try Waziup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the most of your &amp;lsquo;my first Waziup&amp;rsquo; experience, we suggest you start with the &lt;a href=&#34;documentation/installation/hello-world/&#34;&gt;Waziup Hello World app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;admonition note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try the &lt;a href=&#34;documentation/installation/hello-world/&#34;&gt;Hello World app&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;documentation/tutorials&#34;&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read about the &lt;a href=&#34;documentation/how-waziup-works/architecture-and-components&#34;&gt;Waziup architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the &lt;a href=&#34;documentation/installation/&#34;&gt;installation docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See Waziup in action</title>
      <link>/why-use-waziup/see-waziup-in-action</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-use-waziup/see-waziup-in-action</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch the video of &lt;a href=&#34;./documentation/installation/&#34;&gt;Waziup installation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/peHkDhiH3lE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/YsKbJeeav_M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP use cases</title>
      <link>/why-use-waziup/use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-use-waziup/use-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP cutting-edge IoT PaaS platform and software framework support to develop 1000 of IoT applications, out of the box. Any IoT application that you can imagine. Due to the PaaS nature WAZIUP IoT PaaS platform enable you to easy and rapid IoT application development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agriculture:&lt;/strong&gt; The smart farming applications may include monitoring of soil moisture, continuous monitoring of water storage tanks and field conditions (weather/rainfall, soil moisture, electrical conductivity, etc.) and agro-management decisions (date of sowing, irrigation, fertilizing, tilling). For example, farmers will be able to monitor the temperature of grain bins (storage areas) and receive an alert if the temperature rises outside of an acceptable range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fish farming:&lt;/strong&gt; WAZIUP platform enables you to connect a network of sensors to monitor the fish ponds in real time, measuring water temperature, quality, oxygen levels and other parameters. This will improve the current farm management process by giving farmers the ability to monitor their ponds remotely and in a near real-time way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water:&lt;/strong&gt; WAZIUP platform enables you to monitor the pond water quantity, supply, treatment, transportation and storage, flood monitoring. A water management system based on IoT for rural areas and developing countries can help the Community representative monitor and manage water use more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart City:&lt;/strong&gt; WAZIUP supports to develop various smart city applications like urban waste management, public transportation, street-light monitoring, traffic monitoring, smart parking, waste water management, urban air pollution, tourism, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cattle firms:&lt;/strong&gt; Cattle rustling is one of the main problem in developing countries. WAZIUP platform can offer farmer to monitor real-time the cattle situation in order to have viable solution to prevent a theft. The Farmer will receive alert for any critical condition especially the theft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthcare:&lt;/strong&gt; WAZIUP enables for remote monitoring of patients for example real-time monitoring the pregnant woman, patient with diabetics and high-blood pressure, ambient assisted living for the elderly people, child nutrition, and varies wearable applications for activities and health monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logistic:&lt;/strong&gt; WAZIUP Logistic use case may connect “rural” areas (the goods) with the urban areas (the deliveries). The supply chain Ensure that goods (vegetables, fishes) are delivered in an efficient, safe and timely manner to address food safety. The potential case study are tracking the fleet, check the integrity, identification and authentication and traceability of the goods, monitoring the temperature and cooling condition of the goods&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why use WAZIUP?</title>
      <link>/why-use-waziup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-use-waziup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP is an IoT Cloud platform that allows you to create and deploy your IoT applications both in the Cloud and on the IoT gateway. WAZIUP offers &amp;ldquo;out-of-box&amp;rdquo; complete solutions from sensors nodes to applicatons. WAZIUP is particularly adapted to tough conditions, for example for low power and long distance applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simply and easy to deploy the applications (create, push and run)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer Do-it-Yourself sensors nodes and Gateway solutions (few hours to setup the WAZIUP lORA network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long Range and low power IoT communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The platform can handle unreliable and intermitten internet connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WAZIUP offers very low cost hardware as well as application developmet solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple fall-back communicaton options (3G, Wifi, BL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User centric interface design (SME, voice call, mobile app and web app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>